# Luis E Mena Rodriguez

Solutions Arquitect / Technical Lead

## Profile

Computer Science Engineer with 10+ years of experience in roles like: Solutions Architect, Technical Lead and Fullstack Developer. Good at coding standards and problem solving skills, strong knowledge and technical experience in Java and J2EE applications, good knowledge in other languages such as javascript, python, swift, kotlin, php, etc.

Cloud enthusiast, AWS Certified Solutions Architect with experience also in Azure Cloud.

## Employment History

Technical Lead at Banco de Crédito e Inversiones (BCI), Santiago

February 2019 — Present

My team builds the Android and iOS application for BCI, as well building and supporting server-side APIs for the frontend clients.

- Account movements, payment of basic services and credit cards are some of the projects that we have developed in the application so far
- Architect and technical lead of the virtual assistant for BCI.
- Some of the technologies and tools used: Java, Swift, Kotlin, Spring boot, Docker, Kubernetes, Azure Cloud

# Technical Lead / Senior Software Developer at Nisum Latam, Santiago March 2016 — February 2019

Technical Lead and Senior Software Engineer for a variaty of clients and projects.

- Technical Lead in Sodimac, responsible for building a microservices arquitecture for the home delivery product, also we migrate the legacy frontend application for a new one using Angular.
- Fullstack engineer at Scotiabank, I worked on a new product for Scotiabank Chile called High Interest Savings Accounts (HISA).
- Frontend engineer in Bloomingdale's. Member of Credit Services team, focusing on providing a friction-less credit experience for customers.
- Some of the technologies and tools used: Java, Javascript, Spring boot,
  Docker, Kubernetes, Amazon Web Services, React, NodeJs, AngularJs

## Senior Software Developer at Soltein S.A., Quito

February 2014 — February 2016

Fullstack developer on the Odoo suite written in python, Odoo is a management software to run a company. Member of a team in charge of the development of electronic invoicing, human resources and accounting modules both in the frontend and backend.

• Electronic billing solution for Ecuador, oriented to legal regulations in correspondence with the Ecuadorian Electronic Commerce Law.

#### **Details**

Santiago, Chile, +56982474168 lemena86@gmail.com

#### Links

LinkedIn

#### **Skills**

Amazon Web Services (AWS)

Microsoft Azure

Java

Javascript

Python

Sql

Kotlin

Swift

Spring Framework

**RESTful Apis** 

Microservices Arquitecture

Agile Methodologies

React

**AngularJS** 

NoSql

Alexa

Google Assistant

## Languages

Spanish

English

- Information processing and loading module for the database of the "Dirección Nacional de Registro de Datos Públicos de Ecuador", with more than 4TB of information on clients' financial information. Credit score calculation, debt behavior, investments, etc.
- Some of the technologies and tools used: Java, Python, Javascript, Spring boot, Django, PostgresSql

## Software Developer at Desoft S.A., La Habana

September 2012 — February 2014

Desoft it is a software solutions company with over 20 years experience in the IT sector. It offers service lines which includes the development, deployment and support of enterprise management solutions for human resource management, accounting and finance, energy resources, business intelligence, among others.

 Some of the technologies and tools used: Java, Python, Javascript, Spring Framework, PostgresSql, MySql

## Software Developer at Informatic Science University, La Habana

September 2010 — August 2012

As a student and later a graduate student of the university I was part of different projects mainly as a Java backend developer.

- "Sistema de Gestión Penitenciario de Venezuela", I worked as a backend developer in different modules of the system.
- Member of the team who developed "Reko", an structural database replication product, multidirectional with ETL capabilities, compatible with Oracle, PostgreSQL, Berkeley DB, SQLServer, MySQL.
- Some of the technologies and tools used: Java, Javascript, Spring Framework, Dojo, Apache Tomcat, etc.

### Education

## Computer Sciences Engineering, Informatic Science University, La Habana

September 2005 — July 2010

Graduated with honors, 5.22 GPA in a 5 point-scale.

## Certifications

**AWS Certified Solutions Architect - Associate** 

https://www.youracclaim.com/badges/24f878c7-4db9-4944-a7e3-ced1482eb18e

Oracle Certified Associate, Java SE 8 Programmer

https://www.youracclaim.com/badges/fbd431ca-bb63-4c8b-bca4-0d6aa65392a0

**Scrum Foundation Professional Certificate** 

https://www.youracclaim.com/badges/34a98b67-7fed-4c64-a270-4b31cf681aa2

**Microsoft Certified: Azure Fundamentals** 

https://www.youracclaim.com/badges/7673f9ea-cd64-401a-a2f3-970d8598053e